<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS3STHLM</title>
    <description>CS3sthlm, the premier Cyber Security Conference for ICS/SCADA and Critical Infrastructure, annually in October with pre-summit Trainings and Expo.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 08:05:49 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 08:05:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sandworm: Lessons From the Ukrainian Cyberwar and Beyond</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/photos/andy-greenberg-sandworm.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;Sandworm: Lessons From the Ukrainian Cyberwar and Beyond&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the upcoming CS3sthlm Summit (23-24 Oct 2019) in Stockholm, Sweden, attendees can listen to a keynote presentation by Wired senior writer Andy Greenberg. In his not yet released book, Sandworm, that will be distributed to the CS3 attendees, he tells a chilling story about identifying and tracking an elite team of agents bent on digital sabotage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A detailed description of the book, made by the publisher, describes it as follows:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in 2014, the world witnessed the start of a mysterious series of cyberattacks. Targeting American utility companies, NATO, and electric grids in Eastern Europe, the strikes grew ever more brazen. They culminated in the summer of 2017, when the malware known as NotPetya was unleashed, penetrating, disrupting, and paralyzing some of the world’s largest businesses – from drug manufacturers to software developers to shipping companies. At the attack’s epicenter in Ukraine, ATMs froze. The railway and postal systems shut down. Hospitals went dark. NotPetya spread around the world, inflicting an unprecedented ten billion dollars in damage – the largest, most devastating cyberattack the world had ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackers behind these attacks are quickly gaining a reputation as the most dangerous team of cyberwarriors in history: a group known as &lt;strong&gt;Sandworm&lt;/strong&gt;. According to many different sources they working in the service of Russia’s military intelligence agency, and they represent a persistent, highly skilled force, one whose talents are matched by their willingness to launch broad, unrestrained attacks on the most critical infrastructure of their adversaries. They target government and private sector, military and civilians alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keynote-at-cs3sthlm-on-thursday-oct-24th&quot;&gt;Keynote at CS3sthlm on Thursday Oct 24th&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;blog-image blog-image-right&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/speakers/andy-greenberg.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Andy Greenbergs keynote at CS3sthlm on Thursday morning Oct 24th 2019 will he highlight the main lessons from the Ukrainian Cyberwar and beyond, inspired by experiences from his upcoming book “Sandworm - A new era of cyberwar and the hunt for the kremlin’s most dangerous hackers”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joseph Cox, Motherboard, who have read a preview copy of the book make a comment on Twitter: “God damn it’s gripping”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other comment that it’s a chilling, globe-spanning detective story, which considers the danger these type of cyberwarriors poses to national security and stability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, foreign government manipulations comes into focus, which exposes the realities of todays global digital offensive, and the era where warfare ceases to be waged on the battlefield. It reveals how the line between digital and physical conflict, between wartime and peacetime, have begun to blur – with world-shaking implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees at the CS3sthlm Summit in Stockholm will receive a copy of the upcoming book Sandworm, before its release in November.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm---an-event-for-increased-cybersecurity-in-critical-infrastructure&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm - an event for increased cybersecurity in critical infrastructure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3sthlm is the premier annual international industrial cybersecurity event in Northern Europe. The sixth edition of the CS3sthlm Summit takes place in October 23-24 at Nalen in Stockholm, Sweden. The objectives of CS3sthlm is not only to present the latest development and trends from international experts and researchers, but also to establish a platform where people and organizations can share experience and knowledge among peers in order to better protect our civilization against cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/sandworm-lessons-from-ukrainian-cyberwar-beyond/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/sandworm-lessons-from-ukrainian-cyberwar-beyond/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter September</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In Sweden it is still September for a couple of hours!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we will have presentations at multiple stages, so you have to cherry pick your favorites, or bring a colleague if you need to cover things in parallel! And as you can see below, it is really good to go to Stockholm already on Monday, even if the conference as such begins wednesday!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;news-and-highlights&quot;&gt;News and highlights&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download the &lt;strong&gt;CS3sthlm app&lt;/strong&gt; from Appstore or Google Play to keep up to date with info before and during the CS3sthlm week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Torstein Gimnes Are, Digital Marshall &amp;amp; CISO in Norsk Hydro will deliver &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday keynote&lt;/strong&gt; and describe how his team in their international corporation battled a major ransomware attack earlier this year. This presentation will give unique opportunities to listen and learn about global incident and crisis management at an organisation where ICS is the lifeblood of the operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday keynote&lt;/strong&gt; will be given by Andy Greenberg, award-winning senior writer for Wired magazine, where he covers security, privacy, information freedom, and hacker culture. His presentation is based on his upcoming book SANDWORM, about a mysterious series of cyberattacks and the team behind it. Targeting utility companies, NATO, and electric grids in Eastern Europe, and others, there is a lot to learn from Mr Greenbergs story. All CS3 Summit attendees will get a copy the book, and have possibilities to get it signed, two weeks before the official global release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DHS Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Agency will be hosting a technical &lt;strong&gt;ICS-focused Capture the Flag challenge.&lt;/strong&gt; This CTF is designed to expose analysts to hunting across ICS networks for malicious behavior. With puzzles appropriate for both the beginner and the experienced analyst, all are invited to participate. Challenges include artifacts generated from IT/OT host forensic data, network data (from both bro logs and pcap), and OT equipment actively being exploited by a threat actor. &lt;strong&gt;The ICS CTF will be open daytime Monday and Tuesday.&lt;/strong&gt; Mail us at &lt;a href=&quot;info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt; and announce your participation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During Monday evening&lt;/strong&gt;, starting around 4 pm, our &lt;strong&gt;partner Kaspersky will host a KIPS game&lt;/strong&gt; where all our conference attendees can join. Enroll here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://invajo.com/event/thecs3sthlmsummitbyomnisiensab/kipscybersecuritysimulationatcs3sthlm&quot;&gt;KIPS registration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daytime Tuesday&lt;/strong&gt; there will be the &lt;strong&gt;CS3sthlm Expo&lt;/strong&gt;, with both exhibition and speakers. Speakers include our partners and academic researchers from KTH and Linköping presenting the latest in their ICS related research. Enroll here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/cs3sthlm-expo-oct-22nd-2019-registration-64817476818&quot;&gt;Expo registration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are still a few seats open at 2 o the 3 trainings: 1 day &lt;strong&gt;Hands-on threat modeling for ICS-OT&lt;/strong&gt; and 2 day &lt;strong&gt;Network ForensICS&lt;/strong&gt;. More info here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/trainings/&quot;&gt;/program/trainings/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At CS3 this year we will have multiple content going on at multiple stages. During &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday afternoon&lt;/strong&gt; at one stage we will have a large number of speakers presenting on cyber ranges, cyber exercise and training. A lot of examples will be based on the &lt;strong&gt;worlds largest red/blue team exercise LockedShields&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from a busy CS3STHLM crew!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2019/09/30/cs3sthlm-newsletter-september.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2019/09/30/cs3sthlm-newsletter-september.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stephen J. Hilt - Trend Micro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a blog post with Stephen J. Hilt, a senior threat researcher at Trend Micro.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;Stephen J. Hilt - Trend Micro&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-name-where-do-you-work-and-what-is-your-profession&quot;&gt;What is your name, where do you work and what is your profession?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stephen Hilt, Trend Micro. I work as a Sr. Threat Researcher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;since-you-have-been-to-cs3sthlm-4sics-before-whats-your-impression&quot;&gt;Since you have been to CS3sthlm (4SICS) before, whats your impression?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 was my first 4SICS and I’ve attended one more in 2016 before the name change. Great conference put on on by great people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-makes-this-area-protection-of-critical-infrastructure-so-interesting&quot;&gt;What makes this area, protection of critical infrastructure, so interesting?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its something that everyone depends on, every day to work. With out critical infrastructure working lots of things go wrong and its fun to work on something that every one depends on, and try to help secure it so that its there for them all the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-can-you-highlight-from-your-upcoming-presentationdemo-at-cs3sthlm-2019&quot;&gt;What can you highlight from your upcoming presentation/demo at CS3sthlm 2019?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My presentation will be about industrial radio insecurities with a major focus on the crane research that we released earlier in the year. No live demos this time, but more stories about what we did, how we did the research and how working with the vendors to solve a unique problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-the-current-state-of-cybersecurity-in-the-markets-where-your-operating-are-the-customers-well-aware-of-the-threats-do-they-have-good-protection-in-place&quot;&gt;What is the current state of cybersecurity in the markets where your operating? Are the customers well aware of the threats? Do they have good protection in place?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a vendor I don’t think I should answer this question as it may sound salesy&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-biggest-challenges-that-you-see-in-the-ics-security-area--now-and-in-5-years&quot;&gt;What are the biggest challenges that you see in the ICS security area,- now and in 5 years?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With malware evolving and more and more systems coming online you’ll see more cross over from Internet markets coming onto ICS networks. Case in point is who would of thought ransomware would be bringing down factories?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-you-looking-forward-to-with-this-years-cs3sthlm&quot;&gt;What are you looking forward to with this year’s CS3sthlm?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussions with like minded individuals that also want to help solve some of the problems the world is facing in the age of internet security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-would-be-your-advice-to-our-readers-and-attendees&quot;&gt;What would be your advice to our readers and attendees?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engage with the speakers, ask questions, get the most out of your time by making sure you have a true gasp of what they are presenting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/stephen-j-hilt/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/stephen-j-hilt/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter August</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;lots-of-interesting-news-on-our-upcoming-event&quot;&gt;Lots of interesting news on our upcoming event!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-expo-on-22nd-october&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Expo on 22nd October!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday Oct 22, on the day before the CS3sthlm Summit starts, we will have a free of
charge (but registration required) Expo day at our venue Nalen where our partners will display
the latest cyber security solutions and services. We will have a full lineup of speakers during the
Expo day. Free registration here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3-expo-day-2019.eventbrite.com/&quot;&gt;https://cs3-expo-day-2019.eventbrite.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zombie-survival&quot;&gt;Zombie Survival!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be the subject on Wednesday Oct 23rd when our annual CS3sthlm Gala Dinner
speaker enters the stage! We are very proud to announce Herman Geijer, author and zombie
survival expert, who will talk about surviving catastrophes using a zombie scenario!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training-time&quot;&gt;Training time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are only limited amounts of seats left on our three different trainings that will take place
 before the CS3sthlm Summit, so are you thinking about attending them do reserve your spot
 soon: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/trainings/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se/program/trainings/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summit-agenda&quot;&gt;Summit agenda?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, not yet. We have an impressive line-up of speakers already but we are still waiting for a
couple more answers, and that logistics are set. You can see our line-up of speakers here -
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&lt;/a&gt;
and presentations here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ics-lab-news&quot;&gt;ICS lab news&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even bigger and better this year! And a completely new feature is that the CS3sthlm ICS lab will
be open already on Monday Oct 21st! From 9AM to 8PM you are welcome to try out all new
and old gadgets, many of them otherwise unavailable for testing. You will also be able to try out
our challenges and meet other ICS security pros!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hotel-discount&quot;&gt;Hotel discount&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have not yet booked your stay in Stockholm, please check the portal that hotel Elite
Stockholm Plaza have made for out attendees. The hotel is situated only 200 meters from our
venue, Nalen, and the fixed prices that they are offering are valid until Sept 23rd.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elite.se/en/conference-reservations/stockholm/e1a64817-7910-4517-bff8-d94ea2e28ed5/d3e7bea3-f79f-42fa-86bb-b6b5ee1045e2/&quot;&gt;https://www.elite.se/en/conference-reservations/stockholm/e1a64817-7910-4517-bff8-d94ea2e28ed5/d3e7bea3-f79f-42fa-86bb-b6b5ee1045e2/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2019/08/30/cs3sthlm-newsletter-august.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2019/08/30/cs3sthlm-newsletter-august.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter June</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally some news about the 6th CS3STHLM summit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our website is starting to be updated with information on the upcoming conference. A lot of new information has been published, and a lot more will be posted in the near future. Please check it out at this link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Call For Participation, we got more than 65+ very good submissions from all over the planet. We have selected some submissions to start with in this year’s program. Please check out the first batch of topics and presenters listed here &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;speakers&lt;/a&gt; and here &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&quot;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; We will add presenters to the lists over time, as we also have a few slots reserved for invited speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment we have two trainings to chose from, but we hope to have even more very soon. The trainings that are set by today are &lt;strong&gt;ICS/SCADA Penetration Testing&lt;/strong&gt; with Arnauld Souille and &lt;strong&gt;ICS Network ForensICS&lt;/strong&gt; with Erik Hjelmvik. Information on available trainings at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/trainings/&quot;&gt;/program/trainings&lt;/a&gt;. If you already have bought a ticket to the CS3STHLM Summit, or if you just wish to participate in the training part, please contact us at &lt;a href=&quot;info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to add any training. &lt;strong&gt;Discount 10% for COMBO tickets training + summit until end of July!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last year we had a success with our CS3STHLM Expo day held the day before the actual summit. The Expo day is free of charge and gave the attendees a chance to get useful knowledge through our partners and to participate in different activities. For the persons that like the hands-on approach to Cyber Security this is a good day to try out our ICS lab that will be filled with old and new ICS gadgets, many of them otherwise unavailable for testing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also – all video filmed presentations from CS3STHLM 2018 and earlier are now available on our YouTube channel:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkD15o_9eJxUc9eeHtWSQ6Q&quot;&gt;YouTube/cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt;
Please subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2019/06/28/cs3sthlm-newsletter-june.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2019/06/28/cs3sthlm-newsletter-june.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter February</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3sthlm-logo-heart.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Holiday&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-2-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first newsletter of the new year - and it is a short one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The CFP for CS3STHLM 2019 is now open. Please give us your presentations/topics for trainings or workshops before March 29. Also, if you have any suggestions for who you would like to see at the CS3STHLM 2019 summit - send us a mail to cfp@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can buy tickets with Early Bird 20% discount until March 31. The ticket can later be combined with a ticket for training/workshop.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More material from CS3STHLM 2018 is now published on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkD15o_9eJxUc9eeHtWSQ6Q&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cordial greetings from the CS3STHLM crew!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2019/02/15/cs3sthlm-newsletter-february.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2019/02/15/cs3sthlm-newsletter-february.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter December</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3-holiday.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Holiday&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-3-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM 2018 summit had several Top speaker presentations from from different angles of Cybersecurity, SCADA and Industrial Control Systems. As a holiday gift for you, we are now starting to publish presentations on our YouTube channel:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/youtube&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se/youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next year we will be back for the sixth edition of CS3STHLM and the dates are October 21st-24th – &lt;strong&gt;mark your calendars!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM 2019 Trainings will be Monday – Tuesday 21-22&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM 2019 Expo day Tuesday October 22&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM 2019 Summit starts Wednesday Oct 23 and ends Thursday October 24.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another holiday gift is that we already have opened the ticket sale for 2019 with a special &lt;strong&gt;Earliest Bird&lt;/strong&gt; discount of 30 % on the two-day conference ticket. Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tickets.cs3sthlm.se/&quot;&gt;tickets.cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt; and the discounted ticket is available until January 31st. You can add training sessions to this ’summit only’ ticket at a later point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very happy holiday season - from all of us, to all of you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The CS3STHLM crew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Per request we have also added a number of vouchers, each valid for SEK 5.000kr, that later can be used for any CS3STHLM 2019 related cost like training, Expo or summit. If you still have budget to spend, that is!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2018/12/19/cs3sthlm-newsletter-december.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2018/12/19/cs3sthlm-newsletter-december.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Summary of 2018 Event</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;appreciated-expansion-of-acclaimed-cyber-security-conference&quot;&gt;APPRECIATED EXPANSION OF ACCLAIMED CYBER SECURITY CONFERENCE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This years edition of CS3STHLM presented an Expo Day as well as an extended interaction between participants and panelists. 10 students from Norway and Sweden were invited to take part of a challenge which resulted in two students from Norway and Sweden winning a reward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spot The Honey Pot was a challenge initiated by Mikael Vingaard (DK) for participants to find Honey Pots within the ICS networks, won by Matan Dobrushin from Otorio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key Note Speaker on Thursday, Patrick Miller (US), praised the summit for not just high quality content, but also great production, great atmosphere and great venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The founders of CS3STHLM, Robert Malmgren and Erik Johansson, thanked the 200 some participants, speakers, panelists and crew and rounded up the 2018 summit with a poll for Speaker of The Year, and this years winners are Erwin Kooi and Rick van Hees with their presentation The good, the bad and the segmented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS3STLHM 2019 will take place at Nalen in Stockholm October 21-24&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2018/10/25/cs3sthlm-summary-of-2018-event.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2018/10/25/cs3sthlm-summary-of-2018-event.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Record Attendance</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;fifth-edition-of-acclaimed-cyber-security-summit-sees-record-attendance&quot;&gt;FIFTH EDITION OF ACCLAIMED CYBER SECURITY SUMMIT SEES RECORD ATTENDANCE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first conference day founders Robert Malmgren and Erik Johansson are pleased to state that the years conference is the most successful so far, both in attendance and format. The new expo day added a welcome meeting arena for businesses, legislators and other stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second day of the summit will open with Key Note Patrick Miller (US) and his presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;industrial-technology-trajectory-running-with-scissors&quot;&gt;Industrial Technology Trajectory: Running With Scissors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innovative and disruptive technologies are enhancing and invading our traditional industrial business model. Future infrastructure organizations will need more data to operate efficiently and succeed in the brave new interconnected world. The diversity of new technologies and data will fuel more diversity in business opportunity. Everyone expects more OT, more IOT, and more IT - and all of it is supposed to be highly reliable and secure. These factors (and more) lead to a landscape shift for the industrial cybersecurity risk profile. In this session, hear ways to recognize the problems and gain some clarity on possible solutions through historic lessons, made up words, and practical front-line experience.a&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2018/10/24/cs3sthlm-record-attendence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2018/10/24/cs3sthlm-record-attendence.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM App and Honey Pot Competition</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-launches-conference-app&quot;&gt;CS3STHLM LAUNCHES CONFERENCE APP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the conference opens for the 5th consecutive year participants can download an app with agenda, presentations of speakers, and the possibility of partaking in polls, give direct response to seminars, lectures and questions asked from stage. This also means a channel for newsflashes, changes in the program and messages from conference management. You find the app in usual app stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;honey-pot-chase-competition&quot;&gt;HONEY POT CHASE COMPETITION&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mikael Vingaard, (DK), invites all participants to a competition to find Honey Pots: Can you spot the honey-pot(s) @ the ICS Lab? - challenge yourself and find the honey-pot(s) hidden - submit your findings and win a prize!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;spot-the-honey-pot---the-rules-of-engagement&quot;&gt;“Spot the Honey-pot” - The rules of engagement;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition starts 24.oct Wednesday at 10.00 am and ends Thursday at 14.30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The winner will be announced during the closing session, and need to be in the audience during the closing session.
Use whatever tools (e.g. telnet, nmap, PLCscan etc) to find the honeypot(s), we have placed @ the ICS Lab industrial networks!
Be a good ICS neighbor, don’t try to change the configuration on anything, DDOS’ing or otherwise break stuff on purpose - or in any way make the competition harder for your fellow contesters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may work together as a team, but only one prize is rewarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To keep things interesting, we will change the Honeypot environment, during the whole CS3sthlm conference.
There might be many honey-pots hidden - and not only on one single ICS networks - so do remember to look at ICS_Lab network 1 to 4.
In case, that several contesters gets the same (correct) reply - there will be a drawing, to find the winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To participate, do send an email with the following to stockholm@defenica.com before Thursday 14.30 :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a) Your name&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b) time of your research - aka. the date+ Hour as we will dynamically change the honeypot(s) during CS3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;C) IP’s of the honeypots you have spotted - do remember to write on what ICS_LAB network it was found, e.g. IP x.x.x.x on ICS network 4 + IP z.y.y.y on ICS network 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GPDR stuff; the information collected during “Spot the Honeypot” will only be used for this competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May the best honey-pot spotter win :-)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2018/10/22/cs3sthlm-app-and-honey-pot-competition.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2018/10/22/cs3sthlm-app-and-honey-pot-competition.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
