<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS3STHLM</title>
    <description>CS3sthlm, the premier Cyber Security Conference for ICS/SCADA and Critical Infrastructure, annually in October with pre-summit Trainings and Expo.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 07:48:21 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 07:48:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM seventh conference on Cyber Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This years Summit on Cyber Security in Industrial Control Systems and Critical Infrastructure takes place in October 21-22 – but in cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 is looking forward to a successful meeting for leading cyber security experts from around the world. This year the event will be virtual due to the pandemic situation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;robert-malmgren-from-omnisiens&quot;&gt;Robert Malmgren from Omnisiens:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We had to adapt to the situation, and it took us a long time to find a way to move our event to a virtual platform without losing quality or content. Now we are proud and happy to once again announce an impressive line-up of speakers, covering a broad spectra of knowledge in the Cyber Security sphere. We have also brought with us the same production professionals that we usually work together with, to ensure quality and to try to transfer some of the CS3STHLM feeling onto the virtual stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new feature for CS3STHLM is that all material later will be available as VoD, Video on Demand, for all ticket holders. This is to make the content easily accessible at all times, compensating for the time zones differences around the globe.
 
The CS3STHLM Partner Expo, usually arranged the day before the CS3STHLM Summit, is now integrated into the two days of the Summit, and the conference participants can visit exhibitors in the platforms Expo section, or take part in partner sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM Expo is not only a great opportunity to network and discuss the market field for interested parties, but will also consist of exciting demonstrations and presentations from researchers and vendors says Erik Johansson from Omnisiens.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/press/2020/09/24/cs3sthlm-seventh-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press/2020/09/24/cs3sthlm-seventh-conference.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>press</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter September</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3-ticket-2020.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Thank You&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-2-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News on our upcoming event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-virtual-summit-of-2020&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Virtual Summit of 2020!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional CS3 Summit content, presentations, partner exhibitions and social events will be happening online on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hopin.to/events/cs3sthlm-2020&quot;&gt;Hopin platform&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of travelling to Stockholm, you can now participate in the CS3STHLM event from wherever you want. And to counter time zone differences and offer the best accessibility, you can as a ticket holder, either participate in the live event (CET Stockholm time zone Oct 21-22), or watch it later as VOD, Video on Demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tickets-are-for-sale&quot;&gt;Tickets are for sale!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the ticket here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is EUR 299 (including VAT 25%) and is not refundable. When buying tickets, you will have to register name and email on the Hopin platform. Then you will first receive a simple transaction receipt via Hopin, but you will also receive a detailed receipt via email from CS3STHLM within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-trainings-&quot;&gt;No trainings ☹&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, but we could not manage to move the trainings into our virtual platform this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-expo&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Expo!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Expo will be running in parallel on the platform during the CS3sthlm Summit Oct 21-22. Do visit our partners and check out their virtual exhibitions and sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-summit-agenda&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Summit agenda!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the Summit agenda here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/agenda/&quot;&gt;/agenda&lt;/a&gt;. Do also check out our impressive line-up of speakers here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;/speakers&lt;/a&gt;
and you can find the presentations here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&quot;&gt;/presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/09/17/cs3sthlm-newsletter-septepmber.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/09/17/cs3sthlm-newsletter-septepmber.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Goes Virtual</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID situation is problematic for all. For a long time we waited to see if it would be possible to run CS3 in Nalen as we have done for the last 5 years. We have now, after many meetings and discussions, decided to go fully virtual for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional courses, presentations and social events will exist, but go online. We will add new formats and ideas, such as meetups, to the 2020 edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details will be posted in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3sthlm team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/07/10/cs3sthlm-goes-virtual.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/07/10/cs3sthlm-goes-virtual.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Locked Shields Sessions</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;The Locked Shields Sessions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LockedShields is the largest global cyber exercise. It is hosted by the NATO CCDCOE center in Tallinn, Estonia and runned once a year and involves 1000’s of people from many contries around the world. It is very technical, where a number of blue teams need to defend the society from highly sofisticated cyber attacks from a very large and advanced red team. The red team attacks telecom infrastructure, power utilities, water treatment plants, advanced cloud and virtualisation solutions, and the rest of the information infrastructure that make up a modern society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, people around the world received word that the the worlds largest red/blue team cybersecurity exercise, Locked Shields, will be cancled 2020 due to the current situation with Covid-19 all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very unfortunate situation for all involved - the people who have spent 1000’s of hours preparing the exercise, all the teams eager awaiting startex, and people wanting to evaluate the exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this situation there are at least some nuggets to be found - we are releasing 7 videos on Locked Shields that was recorded at CS3 2019 at our special coverage of cyber exercise &amp;amp; Lock Shield. At that session  all different aspects of running a global, multi-team, highly technical cyber exercise were covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction and overview of the whole exercise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the The NATO CCDCOE&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How the green team build the large infrastructure that host all teams and all activities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How red teams plan and perform their attacks,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How blue teams work when they are under large scale attacks from competent adversaries,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How the yellow team, how some experts can be the magic glue and isolation between the blue and the white teams for factual and critical information.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How the white team is keeping track what is happening and keeping the scores&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How the strategic decision making track was created and handled&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More detailed information on these presentations and videos can be found at the archived CS3sthlm site for 2019, please check out the wednesday track &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/2019/agenda/&quot;&gt;/2019/agenda/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/the-locked-shields-sessions/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/the-locked-shields-sessions/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Submissions to the 2020 CFP</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;Submissions to the 2020 CFP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the deadline of the 2020 CFP submission getting closer we have started to get some great submissions, but we are always looking for more content to get a good mix. We welcome presenters from the whole globe, and so far we have had people presenting from most continents, except Australia and the both poles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to have a good balance of policy and technical presentations since we want to have a mixed audience that needs to be exposed to all parts of the protection of critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can always see some interesting examples of IIoT, incident response, successful deployment of new technology, new security research, low-level attacks, new models and methods to discover attacks. A full list of various areas and special topics of interest is included in the info PDF (see  below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For several years we have had authors presenting - such as Kim Zetter, Andy Greenberg, Rob M Lee etc - and have had their books distributed to participants as part of their talks. If you are an author in this field, please consider contacting us to present and we will discuss possibilities for book signing, book distributions, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the general information page on CFP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/call-for-participation/&quot;&gt;/call-for-participation/&lt;/a&gt; and you find the PDF describing the CPF here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/assets/pdf/cs3sthlm-cfp-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;/cs3sthlm-cfp-2020.pdf&lt;/a&gt; and the submission page here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/assets/pdf/cs3sthlm-cfp-submission-form-2020.pdf&quot;&gt;/cs3sthlm-cfp-submission-form-2020.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that the deadline is the 15th of March, and the e-mail address for submissions is cfp@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- CS3STHLM Crew&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/submissions-to-the-2020-cfp/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/submissions-to-the-2020-cfp/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter February</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are announcing the CS3STHLM 2020 Call For Presentations, which of course also includes suggestions for Trainings and Workshops! Submission deadline is set on March 15, and notifications will start a month later. See the submission details at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/call-for-participation/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se/call-for-participation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please do take a moment to read our all-embracing Code of Conduct, it is formed as a vision test for reasons! You can find it on our web page under Practical Details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are closely watching the outbreak of the Coronavirus (COVID-19) but it is at this point too soon to see how this will affect the situation in October. More news to come on this issue, but we have started to form a plan B. And a plan C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM 2020 Theme is Smarter! because our aim is that we all get smarter as a result of the event! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/blog/cs3sthlm-2020-theme-smarter/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se/blog/cs3sthlm-2020-theme-smarter/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you found our YouTube channel: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/cs3sthlm&quot;&gt;youtube.com/cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt; yet? All videos from CS3STHLM 2019 will be published there, apart from the opt-out ones, of course. 
Please subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not forget - Early Bird discount 20% for summit tickets until end of March 2020!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These Summit-only tickets can later be combined with tickets for trainings and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/02/20/cs3sthlm-newsletter-february.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/02/20/cs3sthlm-newsletter-february.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM 2020 Theme Smarter!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3sthlm-heart.png&quot; class=&quot;blog-content-image-half&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 Theme Smarter!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-have-chosen-smarter-as-the-theme-for-the-2020-conference&quot;&gt;We have chosen &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Smarter!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as the theme for the 2020 conference.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons for this selection: “Smart” is used to describe many current things in the cyber industry – such as “SmartGrid”, “Smart Meters”, “Smart Cities” and “smart vehicles”. Smarter is also what the adversaries have become, finding more exotic vulnerabilities, and launching attacks built with increasing domain knowledge and sophistication. We, as people working in this profession, must be smarter, and we must design and implement smarter methods, tactics and solutions to be able to detect and protect against these attacks.   At the same time, we cannot forget that we live in a complicated world where “stupid” still is a highly viable option: “Admin/admin” is still used as login combinations! End-of-life firewalls are still in use! Old bugs are forever days as updates are not done! And separation of sensitive infrastructure from the rest of the business is still not done!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We anticipate submissions from speaker candidates that will be describing new and smart solutions. We also expect presentations that analyses, or describes different attacks, on the stupid, on the broken, or even the smart.   No matter the mix of “smarter” or ”stupid” in presentations, trainings and hallway tracks, we know that all participants will be leaving CS3STHLM 2020 Smarter!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/cs3sthlm-2020-theme-smarter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/cs3sthlm-2020-theme-smarter/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2019 Releases of Recordings</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;2019 Releases of Recordings&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are working with releasing recordings from the 2019 conference. They
are added to the youtube channel as they gets finished (edited, mixed),
and after we receive the OK from the presenter. Videos are available at 
the following URL &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/cs3sthlm&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have gotten some questions about the keynotes: Andy Greenberg and
Norsk Hydro Ransomware attack. The Hydro Ransomware attack was presented
with the condition that it would not be recorded and published. So if
you attended the conference you got an exclusive brefing which others
will miss. We agreed with Andy Greenberg to delay his Sandworm keynote,
since he is currently on a book tour. The recording of the Sandworm
keynote will be released later this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will also add a movie archive at the cs3sthlm home page, from where
one can reach all recordings from previous cs3sthlm conferences. We will
announce it via another blog post when that work is finished!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-releases-of-recordings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-releases-of-recordings/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter January</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3-winter.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Thank You&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-2-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the CS3STHLM crew went to 36C3 in Leipzig at the end of December, and we learned the German phrase ”Guten Rutsch!”, to wish everyone a good start of the New Year! That event was also a good start-up for the work with the upcoming CS3STHLM of 2020; lots of interesting talks and new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now starting to publish all captured presentations from CS3STHLM 2019 on our YouTube channel: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/cs3sthlm&quot;&gt;youtube.com/cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First video out is &lt;strong&gt;Erik Hjelmvik&lt;/strong&gt; of NETRESEC, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/erik-hjelmvik/&quot;&gt;/presentations/erik-hjelmvik/&lt;/a&gt;, who gave a technical talk, including demonstrations, of Polarproxy and TLS stripping at the Harlem stage. Erik have synchronized the release of his presentation with a blog article describing in details the techniques and his tool for stripping away TLS encryption shown in the recorded presentation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netresec.com/?page=Blog&quot;&gt;https://www.netresec.com/?page=Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also releasing a recording of &lt;strong&gt;Monta Elkins&lt;/strong&gt; of FoxGuard Solutions &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/monta-elkins/&quot;&gt;/presentations/monta-elkins&lt;/a&gt;, presentation entitled “Nation-State Supply Chain Attacks for Dummies and You Too”. This presentation really made an impression both with the audience and with media, since it was the most noticed talk in press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not forget - Early Bird discount 20% for summit tickets until end of March 2020!&lt;/strong&gt;
These Summit-only tickets can later be combined with tickets for trainings and workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a month we will start the official CFP for CS3STHLM 2020, but you are most welcome to submit your abstracts or ideas already on cfp@cs3sthlm.se!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/01/13/cs3sthlm-newsletter-january.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/01/13/cs3sthlm-newsletter-january.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter October - Thank You</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3sthlm-logo-heart.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Thank You&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-3-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank you!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the organizing side of CS3sthlm, we would like to express our warmest gratitude to everyone involved in making this years Summit, Expo, lab, trainings, and last but certainly not least the CTF such a success! We would like to give a big shoutout to all content providers, speakers, trainers - without you the event would not have been possible, and it was a honour to work with you! Special thanks goes out to our partners: Accenture Security, Bedriftsystemer AS, CyberX, Kaspersky, Nozomi Networks, Otorio, Recorded Future and sysctl, and also to the crews at Dynamic Duo, WeAreBryssel, Hell Production, Nikka systems, and all staff at Nalen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have already started the long and winding road towards CS3sthlm 2020. The dates are &lt;strong&gt;October 19-22&lt;/strong&gt; - mark that in your calendars. As alumni attendees, we hope that you know that it will be a high quality conference and that you already can already book tickets for maximum discount until Dec 31. You can find the ticket here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tickets.cs3sthlm.se/default.php&quot;&gt;tickets.cs3sthlm.se/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a content provider - we have already &lt;strong&gt;opened the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:CFP@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;CFP@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for submissions. And if you have critics, comments or ideas for enhancements we would like to hear from you. Everything that can make CS3sthlm even better, we would like to know! Mail us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ideas for topics, presenters, content, areas of special interest, things that earns a deep dive, please reach out to us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;. Your input is important to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once again – thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2019 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2019/10/28/cs3sthlm-newsletter-october.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2019/10/28/cs3sthlm-newsletter-october.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
