<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS3STHLM</title>
    <description>CS3sthlm, the premier Cyber Security Conference for ICS/SCADA and Critical Infrastructure, annually in October with pre-summit Trainings and Expo.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 10:13:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kai Thomsen - Senior Incident Responder</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a blog post with Kai Thomsen, a senior incident responder at AUDI AG.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;Kai Thomsen - Senior Incident Responder&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-day-job-where-are-you-working-and-what-do-you-do&quot;&gt;What is your day job, where are you working and what do you do? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a senior Incident Responder at AUDI AG. My office is in Ingolstadt at Audi’s headquarters, but takes me where ever we have to investigate. Currently we a building up a joint Enterprise/ICS/Car cyber defense team. This means learning about and integrating three sometimes very different mindsets. Quite a challenge, but I’m convinced that we won’t be very successful without these integrated teams. I also teach for SANS in the ICS curriculum. And since we are a small team, I get to teach all over the world, which is at the same time interesting and challenging considering all the different countries and cultures I get to teach in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-how-long-have-you-worked-in-the-field&quot;&gt;For how long have you worked in the field? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computers and hacking have been kind of my thing since I was thirteen. After university, in 2001, when I finally had to get a real job, I got started as a network admin tasked with passive security (firewalls, IDSses, etc.) and then moved on to what nowadays is called active defense, mainly Network Security Monitoring and Incident Response. When Stuxnet hit in 2010 and caused a lot of headache for us at the company I was working at back then I started to focus more on ICS security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;you-give-classes-as-a-technical-trainer-for-icsscada-security-do-you-see-a-lot-of-interest-in-these-issues&quot;&gt;You give classes as a technical trainer for ICS/SCADA security, do you see a lot of interest in these issues? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I teach the “ICS Active Defense and Incident Response” course at SANS (ICS515). And we have definitely seen interest increasing in this and other ICS courses over the last year. When I look at the current threat landscape, this was absolutely necessary. We need a lot more knowledgable and capable active defenders to secure our critical infrastructures and industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-you-ever-destroyed-a-car-or-something-physical-as-part-of-what-you-do-in-your-day-work&quot;&gt;Have you ever destroyed a car, or something physical, as part of what you do in your day work? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, yes, but keep in mind, I am an incident responder, not I researcher so my main mantra especially in ICS/SCADA environments is to always put safety and reliability of operations first. But as probably anyone who as worked on many incidents I have my own stories to tell about devices and thus evidence I destroyed because of a stupid mistake I made.  With regard to what you are probably more interested in, do I crash vehicles with my mad cyber skills, that’s a) not how this works and b) the job of our dedicated Car/IT Security team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-the-hype-in-relation-to-cyber-security-and-vehicles&quot;&gt;What is the hype in relation to cyber security and vehicles? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion the hype is in the way current research gets reported vs. what current threats against vehicles actually are. Most organized crime around vehicles is about stealing vehicles or spare parts. Of course this is not as sexy for a story than say hackers taking over autonomous vehicles. If you’d like to get my full view on this, come to my talk ;-)
What is the biggest challenges to automotive area with regards to security? I think the biggest challenge is software developers and automotive engineers understanding each other’s development processes and constraints. And learning to understand their different culture and language. Without these basics we’ll have a very hard time coping with the paradigm shifts currently happening in the automotive industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-car-theft-the-biggest-risk-or-do-you-see-other-aspects-worse-risks-for-vehicles--cyber-security&quot;&gt;Is car theft the biggest risk, or do you see other aspects worse risks for vehicles &amp;amp; cyber security? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of now I’d say yes, definitely. As cars get more functionality that can be activated via software and we see an increase of managed vehicle fleets versus privately owned cars threats will probably diversify somewhat more. Criminals will always be where the most money can be made with the least risk, at least we can be sure of that ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-the-least-known-aspects-of-cyber-security-in-the-automative-industry&quot;&gt;What is the least known aspects of cyber security in the automative industry? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have been at some aspects of this a lot longer than many folks in the cyber security community might think and this has to do with all the immobilizer technology put into cars over the past 10-15 years and criminals finding ways around that. Also most discussions around fixing security problems in vehicles with quick patches over the air often don’t reflect how much testing has to go into any change you make to anything safety related in a vehicle. Also, like most ICS systems, we should keep in mind that there are (and there probably should be some more) failsafes that cannot be overridden by software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-will-the-creation-of-smart-cities-have-an-impact-on-smart-cars-with-regards-to-security&quot;&gt;How will the creation of smart cities have an impact on smart cars, with regards to security? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Absolutely. It’s the complexity of networks and the questions of trust all over again. But on a much larger scale than the Internet and with larger time constraints on both ways. By that I mean, your car and the traffic light you’re about to be at in 5 seconds won’t have the time to establish trust via something like a CRL. But also, that traffic light will be there for more than twenty years. And your car has a lifetime of about 10-15 years. Lots of interesting questions waiting for answers when it comes to smart cities…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-general-do-you-think-that-we-will-ever-see-things-like-notpetya-ransomware-infecting-cars&quot;&gt;In general, do you think that we will ever see things like NotPetya, ransomware infecting cars? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can certainly imagine wormable vulnerabilities in parts of vehicle infrastructure that heavily relies on software. EV charging infrastructure, I’m looking at you ;-) But I am still optimistic enough that we’ll finally start learning from mistakes in other fields and will succeed in implementing more resilient architectures in vehicles and smart traffic infrastructures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-will-be-the-biggest-take-away-for-the-audience-from-your-presentation-at-cs3sthlm&quot;&gt;What will be the biggest take away for the audience from your presentation at CS3sthlm? &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That although there are some hard questions waiting to be answered we do know the basics of how to do this right. These are not new and sexy things and they take some effort, but it’s certainly doable. Also, we are still very early on in this particular race. So there is still time to learn from other fields and do some things better. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/kai-thomsen/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/kai-thomsen/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter September</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-expo-on-23rd-oct&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Expo on 23rd Oct&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 23rd, we will have an Expo at our venue Nalen. Partners will display the latest cyber security solutions and services. We will have a full lineup of speakers during the Expo day on the Harlem stage. Get the agenda for the day here &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/expo/&quot;&gt;/expo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free registration here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlmexpo.eventbrite.com/?aff=cs3sthlm&quot;&gt;https://cs3sthlmexpo.eventbrite.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Info on Expo partners and new CS3sthlm partners, shown further down!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;technical-training&quot;&gt;Technical Training&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we will offer six different trainings, to have something for all our participants. Some are technical deep dives, some are more theoretical or policy oriented. Here is some short info on the trainings:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/mikael-vingaard/&quot;&gt;Learn why honeypots&lt;/a&gt; should be part of your toolbox to detect anomalies in your ICS network by taking Mikael Vingaards ICS honeypot class. This is a very hands-on class. Read an interview with Mike here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/blog/mikael-vingaard/&quot;&gt;/blog/mikael-vingaard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/erik-hjelmvik/&quot;&gt;The Network ForensICS&lt;/a&gt; class is given for the 3rd time. Always sold out. Packed with network level examinations and protocol analysis, and you need to bring your computer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/stephan-beirer/&quot;&gt;The ISO/IEC 27019&lt;/a&gt; training can be very useful for those interested in policy level work for the oil/gas industry or electrical utility industry. Read an interview with Dr Beirer here   &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/blog/dr-stephan-beirer/&quot;&gt;/blog/dr-stephan-beirer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/arnaud-soullie/&quot;&gt;The ICS Pentest&lt;/a&gt; is a hand-on class where you will learn to find errors and vulnerabilities in a ICS system. To add something little extra, the class also includes a capture-the-flag competition between the attendees.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/joe-slowik&quot;&gt;ICS Strategic planning and war gaming&lt;/a&gt; is given by Joe Slowik of Dragos Inc to help you become better at defending your ICS systems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/ben-daniel/&quot;&gt;Ben and Daniel&lt;/a&gt; from Dragos will get you started with threat hunting in your ICS environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See all trainings here: &lt;a href=&quot;/program/trainings/&quot;&gt;/trainings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;more-speakers&quot;&gt;More Speakers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are more or less ready with the lineup for this year with close to 30 presenters. We have experts from all over the world, giving presentations in as diverse areas such as Cyber attacks against cars, lessons from incidents and attacks, writing a adding malware into blockchain solutions. See all speakers here &lt;a href=&quot;/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;/speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ics-security-lab&quot;&gt;ICS Security Lab&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will continue the success with the ICS security lab from previous years. Attendees will have opportunities to try out various ICS equipment, cyber security protection mechanisms, and to see demonstrations of attacks. More info on the lab here &lt;a href=&quot;/ics-lab/&quot;&gt;/ics-lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hotel-discount&quot;&gt;Hotel Discount&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take note - hotel Elite Stockholm Plaza will only hold the reserved block of rooms for CS3sthlm until the 21st of september. If you have not already booked your hotel room, now is the time! Use this link &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.elite.se/en/conference-reservations/stockholm/e1a64817-7910-4517-bff8-d94ea2e28ed5/ea79fd04-097f-47bc-a55f-5e12e8c5868a/&quot;&gt;https://www.elite.se/en/conference-reservations/stockholm/e1a64817-7910-4517-bff8-d94ea2e28ed5/ea79fd04-097f-47bc-a55f-5e12e8c5868a/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;new-partners&quot;&gt;New Partners&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;partner--list partner--list-inpost&quot;&gt;


	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item partner--item-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.advenica.com/en&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/advenica.png&quot; alt=&quot;Advenica&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item partner--item-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.msb.se/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/msb-english.png&quot; alt=&quot;MSB&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item partner--item-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/first.png&quot; alt=&quot;FIRST&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item partner--item-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://dragos.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/dragos.png&quot; alt=&quot;Dragos&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item partner--item-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kraftcert.no/english/index.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/kraftcert.png&quot; alt=&quot;KraftCERT&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item partner--item-large&quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gai-netconsult.de/index.php?id=startseite&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/gai-netconsult.png&quot; alt=&quot;Gai Netconsult&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://omnisiens.se&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/omnisiens.png&quot; alt=&quot;OMNISIENS&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://romab.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/romab.png&quot; alt=&quot;ROMAB&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://sysctl.se&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/sysctl.png&quot; alt=&quot;sysctl&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;http://managementdoctors.se&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/md.png&quot; alt=&quot;Management Doctors&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaspersky.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/kaspersky.png&quot; alt=&quot;Kaspersky&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.recordedfuture.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/recorded-future.png&quot; alt=&quot;Recorded Future&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://waterfall-security.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/waterfall-security.png&quot; alt=&quot;Waterfall Security&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.energinet.dk&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/energinet.png&quot; alt=&quot;EnergiNet&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netresec.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/netresec.png&quot; alt=&quot;NETRESEC&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://netnordic.se&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/netnordic.png&quot; alt=&quot;Netnordic&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;partner--item &quot;&gt;
		&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.secmatters.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/partners/securitymatters.png&quot; alt=&quot;SecurityMatters&quot; width=&quot;auto&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;
		&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2018/09/19/cs3sthlm-newsletter-september.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2018/09/19/cs3sthlm-newsletter-september.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Erik Johansson - Co-founder of CS3sthlm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a blog post with Ph D Erik Johansson, one of the organizers of the CS3sthlm summit. Below you find the interview we did with him as the planning and preparation of the conference and expo, was in full swing!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;Erik Johansson - Co-founder of CS3sthlm&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behind the scenes: Erik Johansson, CS3sthlm organizer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-name-profession-and-where-do-you-work&quot;&gt;What is your name, profession and where do you work?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My name is Erik Johansson and  I work as an independent advisor helping organizations with assessments and procurements to increase industrial cyber security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often see myself as an Cyber Security Evangelist. Since I have found that most often the root cause behind technical weaknesses comes down to changing organizations mindset by educating and training them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-did-you-get-involved-with-this-conference&quot;&gt;How did you get involved with this conference?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well the ideas for this conference started like a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every winter Robert and I visited S4 the S4 conference in Miami. However, we were surprised about the small number of Europeans over there - despite the lack of  good conferences focusing on Industrial Cyber Security in Europe. The ones that existed was too commercial and lacked the combination of technical depth and business perspective that we thought was necessary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-did-you-get-involved-in-this-field&quot;&gt;How did you get involved in this field?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my  research at the Royal Institute of Technology (KTH) on the security challenges, when migrating from analog to digital equipment (aka programmable electronics), I found that the security could also be related to the mindset of the people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A root cause of technical weaknesses can often be traced back to the lack of understanding the security implications of the business decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last decades have I therefore preached about security awareness for organizations in order to change their fundamentally immature mindset regarding security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About twenty years ago I met Robert Malmgren – a very clever IT-security person who did not only understand the bits and bytes but could also see the business perspective - and the lack of human understanding of the complexity. Since then have our roads crossed many times in security related projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-role-during-the-conference&quot;&gt;What is your role during the conference?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the co-founders,  Robert Malmgren and I are involved in most part of the planning as well as running the event. Involved in program committee, evaluating the submitted papers, selecting partners and perform the overall discussion with industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;running-a-big-event-like-cs3sthlm-is-different-from-your-day-to-day-work-or&quot;&gt;Running a big event like CS3sthlm is different from your day-to-day work, or?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Definitely different. It’s a strange time consuming ”hobby” – that takes a huge amount of our limited spare timet. However, it’s also super exciting to get to know so many clever people from allround this planet… :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-it-a-marathon-race-a-100-meter-race-is-it-cat-herding-or-something-else-to-do-this-kind-of-job&quot;&gt;Is it a marathon race, a 100 meter race, is it cat herding or something else to do this kind of job?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tricky question. It’s really a mix. It’s a Marathon in the way that the planning and preparations starts almost direct after the last one and is ongoing for almost a year. Sometimes it’s more like a 100 meter race - like when we get 50 great submissions that needs to be evaluated. Or when the final program and all pieces is getting in place… and yes we are all exhausted after each event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;why-should-i-go&quot;&gt;Why should I go?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone that is working in critical infrastructure, as manager or operational, and would like to learn more about current threats, incidents, vulnerabilities and experiences as well as success stories should go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not to say the least is to participate in the networking among peers that inspire and share valuable knowledge during the event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-are-the-biggest-challenges-that-you-see&quot;&gt;What are the biggest challenges that you see?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industry have a huge challenge, not only to continuously increase their knowledge and awareness but to get a mature security culture in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenges from a conference perspective is to reach out and bridge the unfortunate gap between top-level decision-makers and technical experts as well as the gap between IT and OT departments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-best-memory-from-previous-conferences&quot;&gt;What is your best memory from previous conferences?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hard to tell - there are so many good memories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One was when the security researcher Ruben Santamarta (IOACTIVE) did a live hacking demo on a critical SATCOM equipment turning into a slot machine in front of our eyes.  Another special memory was to listen to the only Swedish Astronaut, Mr Fuglesang, as evening speaker! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-do-you-look-forward-to-with-this-years-event&quot;&gt;What do you look forward to with this year’s event?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really excited for this our fifth anniversary which has been extended with an EXPO on the day before the SUMMIT!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;any-last-words-of-advice-to-our-readers-and-the-attendees&quot;&gt;Any last words of advice to our readers and the attendees?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Arrive early! Participate and interact with the vendors at the EXPO. Moreover, take the opportunity to discuss the strategical challenges that follows by the ongoing regulations and visit and don’t forget to take a look at the ICS lab and the demonstrations of valuable security solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/erik-johansson/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/erik-johansson/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dr. Stephan Beirer - The Expert on the ISO/IEC 20719 standard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a blog post interview with Dr. Stephan Beirer, the expert on the
ISO/IEC 27019 standard. He will give a training session during the
CS3sthlm conference week. Below you will find an interview we did with
him as he was preparing for the class. You will probably find several
things in the interview that you didnt already knew about the standard!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot;&gt;Dr. Stephan Beirer - The Expert on the ISO/IEC 20719 standard&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-day-job-where-are-you-working-and-what-do-you-do&quot;&gt;What is your day job, where are you working and what do you do?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a Principal Security Consultant and the Team Manager for ICS/OT Security at GAI NetConsult, a security consulting company based in Berlin / Germany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GAI NetConsult has been working in the ICS/OT domain for more than 15 years. Together with my colleagues we do consulting and technical or organizational auditing in the OT and ICS domain, mostly for operators and asset owners from energy industry, industrial manufacturing and for critical infrastructure projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;for-how-long-have-you-worked-in-the-field&quot;&gt;For how long have you worked in the field?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my studies and my PhD, I worked as a freelance security consultant. In 2006, I joined GAI NetConsult; I have been working in the ICS / OT domain since then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;are-you-involved-in-the-standardization-process-what-areas-are-you-working-with&quot;&gt;Are you involved in the standardization process? What areas are you working with?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 2010, I am involved in security standardization for ICS and OT systems. First in the security working group of the German utility organization BDEW, then also in the national standardization institutions DIN and DKE, the German mirror organisation to IEC. Since 2011, I have been working on the international level within ISO and IEC. In the working group responsible for information security management at ISO/IEC, I am the Editor of ISO/IEC 27019 and an expert for ICS and Smart Grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;in-your-class-you-will-cover-the-isoiec-27019-standard-which-is-somewhat-unknown-to-many-what-is-the-background-for-this-standard&quot;&gt;In your class, you will cover the ISO/IEC 27019 standard, which is somewhat unknown to many. What is the background for this standard?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ISO/IEC 27019 started as a German national project in 2010. It was initiated by several large and medium sized energy utilities and BDEW, the German utility association. The utilities felt that it was hard to integrate the OT / ICS domain within their security management organization, which was based on ISO/IEC 27001 within most companies. They decided to publish a standard to fill this gap and in 2013, the German version was translated and published as an international ISO/IEC document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aim of 27019 is to extend the contents of ISO/IEC 27002 to the domain of process control systems and automation technology, thus allowing energy utilities to implement a standardized and specific information security management system (ISMS) that extends from the business to the process control level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;where-you-involved-early-on-with-the-development-of-the-isoiec-27019-standard&quot;&gt;Where you involved early on with the development of the ISO/IEC 27019 standard?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was the project leader and editor for the German version at DIN and DKE from 2010 to 2012 and was then delegated from the German National Body to ISO/IEC to be the Editor of the International Standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-is-a-relatively-new-edition-of-the-standard-does-the-new-version-differ-much-in-comparison-with-older-ones&quot;&gt;There is a relatively new edition of the standard. Does the new version differ much in comparison with older ones?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version from 2017 is now completely aligned with the current version of ISO/IEC 27001 and 27002, so it can be seamlessly used within an ISMS based on ISO/IEC 27001. Additionally we aligned with 27001 in such a way that is possible to have certifications based on ISO/IEC 27019 together with 27001. Furthermore, the scope of the standard has been extended to include the oil sector. We completely revised the technical content of all security controls and twelve new topics are covered now which were not included in the first revision from 2013, e.g. with regard to mobile devices, vulnerability management or technical reviews. 
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;will-utility-companies-start-certification-processes-against-the-27019-standard-or-is-it-still-against-the-27001-only&quot;&gt;Will utility companies start certification processes against the 27019 standard, or is it still against the 27001 only?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to have a certification for ISO/IEC 27019. This automatically includes the ISO/IEC 27001 requirements, which 27019 refers to. In Germany, already all gas and electricity grid providers have to be certified against ISO/IEC 27001 together with ISO´/IEC 27002 and 27019 since January, very likely a similar regulation will come into force for large generation and gas storage plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-there-any-requirement-on-prerequisites-and-prior-deep-knowledge-of-isoiec-27000-before-taking-the-class&quot;&gt;Is there any requirement on prerequisites and prior deep knowledge of ISO/IEC 27000 before taking the class?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Absolutely not. After an introduction to the energy supply and the ICS systems used in the different energy domains, I will give an overview about the ISO/IEC 27000 series and the important content of ISO/IEC 27001, which is necessary to understand the application of 27019. Then we will concentrate on the 27019 controls for the various security management domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;you-will-also-talk-about-an-interesting-german-and-austrian-whitepaper-what-is-the-background-of-this-document&quot;&gt;You will also talk about an interesting German and Austrian Whitepaper. What is the background of this document?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Whitepaper „Requirements for Secure Control and Telecommunication Systems” is a best practice guideline, which defines security requirements for control systems used in the energy domain. It was developed by the German and Austrian utility associations BDEW and Oesterreichs Energie - therefore it is also called BDEW/OE-Whitepaper. The first version was published already in 2008 and it has become the de-facto standard in the German speaking regions, i.e. Germany, Austria and Switzerland for security requirement definitions for control systems in the energy domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In May 2018 a fully revised version 2.0 has been published, the English translation is available is here:  https://www.bdew.de/service/anwendungshilfen/whitepaper-anforderungen-sichere-steuerungs-telekommunikationssysteme/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-does-the-bdewoe-whitepaper-relate-to-isoiec-27019&quot;&gt;How does the BDEW/OE-Whitepaper relate to ISO/IEC 27019?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While ISO/IEC 27019 defines requirements and best-practice controls related to the security management in the utility organization, the BDEW/OE-Whitepaper covers the requirements for the technology used in the ICS/OT domain. It is focusing on security specification and requirement definition in procurement projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together, ISO/IEC 27019 and the BDEW/OE-Whitepaper are the basis for secure operation within an energy utility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-long-have-you-been-working-with-the-bdewoe-whitepaper&quot;&gt;How long have you been working with the BDEW/OE-Whitepaper?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With BDEW and Oesterreichs Energie, I have been the editor of the Whitepaper both for the initial version in 2008 and for the revision in 2018. I have used the Whitepaper very often over the last 10 years, especially in procurement and audit projects for grid control systems, substation automation and protection systems as well as for power and gas storage plant automation and virtual power plants and supporting OT systems. Oddly enough, sometimes I still have to discuss the same problematic topics with suppliers and integrators as ten years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-your-class-only-theoretical-or-will-the-participants-also-have-any-practical-exercises&quot;&gt;Is your class only theoretical, or will the participants also have any practical exercises?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have exercises to learn how to apply the lecture content with regard to the ISO/IEC 27019 controls and the BDEW/OE-Whitepaper requirements. I will give as many first hand experiences from my projects with 27019 and the Whitepaper as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;as-an-expert-in-the-field-of-itinformationcyber-security-any-advice-you-would-like-to-share&quot;&gt;As an expert in the field of IT/information/cyber security, any advice you would like to share?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our field is rapidly changing, thus is very important to have a regular exchange within the community. CS3STHLM is a perfect event for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;any-last-thoughts-you-would-like-to-share-with-the-readers&quot;&gt;Any last thoughts you would like to share with the readers?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy that I have been invited to give a lecture at CS3STHLM. I am looking forward to meet IRL some old friends from the ICS security community and to make a lot of new ones in Stockholm! I heard rumours there might be a gathering of the European Chapter of BEER-ISAC also…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/dr-stephan-beirer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/dr-stephan-beirer/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mikael Vingaard - The Expert on ICS Honeypots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is a blog post with Mikael Vingaard, the expert on ICS Honeypot that will give the 2-day training session during the CS3sthlm conference week. Last year it was a 1 day course, but we decided to extend it so that more could be covered during class. Below you will find an interview we did with Mike as he was preparing for the class.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 class=&quot;blog-title&quot; itemprop=&quot;name headline&quot;&gt;Mikael Vingaard - The Expert on ICS Honeypots&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-your-background-with-regards-to-security-the-energy-system-and-honeypots&quot;&gt;What is your background, with regards to security, the energy system and honeypots?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the last 15 years, I have been working as Pentester, Auditor, BC-manager and IT-security “jack of all trade” like malware tracking and alerting via malware sinkholes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Four years ago I switched from IT security to OT Security and needed to learn a lot of stuff in a very short timespan. As I didn’t have a power substation or water treatment plant for my private disposal (who has that :-) I had to learn a lot on ‘arcane’ ICS protocols like Modbus, IEC104, S7comm, DNP3 in some other way, hence honeypot seemed like an interesting way forward. To sum it all up - I needed to build something to simulate these protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a low interaction honeypot and started to learn about it. After a while I put an ICS honeypot on the Internet, and it was attacked right away! I was hooked and the rest is history - today I manage one of the largest privately owned honeypot networks (120+ sensors) deployed all over the world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;honeypots-arent-they-just-tools-for-researchers-or-can-they-be-used-in-a-real-environment&quot;&gt;Honeypots, aren’t they just tools for researchers? Or can they be used in a real environment?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can be both! During my two-day training at CS3sthlm in October we will touch both types of usage. Depending on your goals and scope, it is two different deployment approaches - they can (read should!) be used as a important layer in our “defense in depth” strategies. Internally deployed honeypots can provide an effective “close-to-zero-false-positives” warning system - with a minimal maintained profile - and should be used in most ICS networks. My newest honeypot project Defenica works as a very, very convincing deception ICS device, built on purpose to emulate for example a PLC or HMI system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-is-the-most-interesting-results-or-effects-you-have-seen-with-your-honeypots&quot;&gt;What is the most interesting results or effects you have seen with your honeypots?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is when I find zero-days targeting my honeypot networks!  Normal reasoning would say that no real attackers would “burn” a zero-day on unsolicited ICS equipment… but some times they do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My latest published Moxa vulnerability (CVE-2018-10632) &lt;a href=&quot;https://ics-cert.us-cert.gov/advisories/ICSA-18-200-04&quot;&gt;https://ics-cert.us-cert.gov/advisories/ICSA-18-200-04&lt;/a&gt; was built on the research found in the network traffic aimed at one of my honeypots!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My 2 day workshop would provide a walk-through on that case, to enable my students to be inspired to do similar zero-day research activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;high-interaction-honeypots-or-low-interaction-honeypots-what-is-that-and-what-do-you-think-about-it&quot;&gt;High interaction honeypots or low interaction honeypots, what is that, and what do you think about it?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honeypots can be either low, medium or high interaction. Low interaction honeypots are very easy to spot as a fake system if the attacker is skilled, but a high interaction honeypot, to a very large extent, has the same feel and look as the device/system that you are emulating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my learning curve I started with typical low interactions honeypots, but today I use only medium/high interaction honeypots. During the workshop we will deploy and work with low, medium and high interaction honeypots – in combination with real ICS/SCADA equipment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;during-your-time-running-honeypots-what-is-the-most-surprising-thing-you-have-encountered-or-seen&quot;&gt;During your time running honeypots, what is the most surprising thing you have encountered or seen?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When moving from low to high interactions honeypots a whole new world of enriched data emerged! Suddenly I found that I was able to detect and track various attacker groups during their campaign. Often one IP address attacks a honeypot, and they do some stuff and then seem to stop and go away. A while later a new IP adress comes along and continues the work that the first IP started!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having deployed a considerably number of honeypots globally, I have been able to see patterns, as well as map various activities to a specific group of attackers, previously hidden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;can-an-attacker-easily-see-the-difference-between-a-real-system-and-a-fake-one-the-honeypot&quot;&gt;Can an attacker easily see the difference between a real system and a fake one, the honeypot?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my class I will share my hard-earned knowledge on how to setup honeypots that an attacker cannot differentiate from a real device!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-would-you-differentiate-the-honeypot-in-comparison-with-an-ids-or-an-ips-what-are-the-advantages&quot;&gt;How would you differentiate the honeypot in comparison with an IDS or an IPS? What are the advantages?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditional IDS/IPS systems are often signature based, hence they will alert you whenever something match a known “signature”. If the activities/signatures from the attacker are not known in advance, no alert will be triggered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the honeypot is a fake unit, there should never be any reason to communicate with the device - so any and all traffic/alerts to or from it should be investigated by the SOC/Blue team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-there-anything-that-you-can-catch-or-detect-or-do-with-an-honeypot-that-one-cannot-do-with-an-ids-ips-or-firewall&quot;&gt;Is there anything that you can catch, or detect, or do with an honeypot that one cannot do with an IDS, IPS or firewall?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical IDS system is designed for operating in environment with traditional IT systems, not OT/ICS equipment. Putting an IDS system to alert on ‘anomaly stuff ‘ e.g. old network protocols in an OT industrial network will fire a lots of alerts and make the security monitor system to light up as a over-charged Christmas three - that not a good way to avoid the alert fatigue that so many SOC/SAC teams are currently suffering from…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As highlighted earlier, a significant advantage of using honeypot technology is the (almost) zero-false positive alerts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-the-honeypot-a-protection-or-a-detection-mechanism&quot;&gt;Is the honeypot a protection or a detection mechanism?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Very good questions, Robert! I would say that a honeypot typically and &lt;em&gt;primarily&lt;/em&gt; is a detection mechanism to alert you that something is out of order. But based on the deployment options it can actually be both!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;having-honeypots-in-a-icsscada-environment-what-is-the-most&quot;&gt;Having honeypots in a ICS/SCADA environment, what is the most&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;important things to think about?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To know what  to achieve from the deployment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to make the honeypot ’believable’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Not introducing new risks for the company&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this, and more, is what we will learn on the first day of the workshop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;if-a-honeypot-actually-is-being-attacked-what-is-the-first-thing-you-should-do-as-the-owner-of-the-honeypot&quot;&gt;If a honeypot actually is being attacked, what is the first thing you should do as the owner of the honeypot?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First: be really happy that it’s a honeypot and not the real equipment the attacker are trying to hack :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly: initiate your incident response (IR) process and start to observe the attacker in order to find the best possible time to kick them out of the environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And - if done properly in the IR phase, be sure to gather knowledge of the TTP’ of the attackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-will-your-students-learn-at-the-training&quot;&gt;What will your students learn at the training?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My students will learn how to plan, build, deploy and manage different types of honeypots. We will deploy the honeypots on the Internet and see various probes and attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second day we will build a dedicated network with real ICS/SCADA equipment and learn how to move from low to high interactions honeypots. Lots of fun stuff to do with this equipment!
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;any-last-final-words-of-advice-you-would-like-to-give&quot;&gt;Any last final words of advice you would like to give?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have honeypots in your arsenal of security tools you are missing out on a very interesting technology that can be effective, with zero false positives. If you never have worked with honeypots, please come and join the technical training!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great bonus of taking the honeypot class is that you also will get a view on the strange and ‘arcane’ protocols that lives in most industrial networks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/mikael-vingaard/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/mikael-vingaard/</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter April</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are opening up the gates for the 5th CS3STHLM summit! In this newsletter we present the keynote speakers, our first presentation and a record number of training sessions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;important-notice&quot;&gt;Important notice!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of you might already be aware of the new data privacy regulations (GDPR) that will be applied in Europe on May 25th. This regulation makes all of our old registers for mail information null and void by the end of May.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to keep receiving our Newsletters with information about the CS3STHLM activities – PLEASE CLICK ON &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;THIS LINK&lt;/a&gt; AND SEND US THE RESULTING MAIL.  We are sorry for this inconvenience, but we feel it is important to respect the privacy of all persons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spring cleaning has been done to our website. We have updated the web with information on the upcoming conference. A lot of new information has been published, and a lot more will be posted in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled and honoured to announce our two keynote speakers for the 2018 CS3Sthlm conference: Marty Edwards and Patrick C. Miller. Both keynote speakers have a long history in ICS security, one working within DHS and the ICS-CERT, the other being the grandfather of the NERC CIP. Both are also very experienced and well-respected speakers at conferences worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the Call For Participation, we got more than 50+ very good submissions from all over the planet. We have selected 16 top submissions to start with in this year’s agenda. Please check out the first batch of topics and presenters listed here &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;/speakers&lt;/a&gt; and here &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&quot;&gt;/presentations&lt;/a&gt; We will add presenters to the lists over time, as we also have a few slots reserved for invited speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have a record number of training sessions to select from this year. It is the largest selection found at any ICS/SCADA conference, which allows you to select deep dives into the topic most interesting for you: ICS/SCADA Penetration Testing, ICS Threat Hunting, ICS Network Defense, ICS Network ForensICS, ISO 27019, ICS Honeypots. Information on trainings available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/trainings/&quot;&gt;/trainings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our strong lineup, with keynotes/presenters/trainings and with yet a number of unannounced speakers and events, is stronger than any of the previous years!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take advantage of the MEDIUM BIRD DISCOUNT of 10% that is still valid until May 31st on all tickets! Please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;https://tickets.cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;ticket site&lt;/a&gt; to claim your discounted ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last, and on the lighter side – we have had some questions regarding the meaning of CS3STHLM. 
“CS3” stands for Cyber Security, Critical Structures and Control Systems, “STHLM” is short for Stockholm where the summit is held annually, and had to be added not to confuse our name with other brands. The correct pronunciation is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;/siː ɛs θriː stɒkhoʊlm/;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or better yet, grab one of the organizers when you are at the conference and ask them why we need such strange name for this thing….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2018/04/30/cs3sthlm-newsletter-april.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2018/04/30/cs3sthlm-newsletter-april.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter December</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3-holiday.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Holiday&quot; class=&quot;full-width-image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2017 was indeed a remarkable year, and some of the cyber security related things that happened will surely be remembered. Among them was the Wannacry malware hospitals, industrial companies and other important infrastructure. Things that also hit the front pages were outbreak that blindly struck against the analysis of Industroyer/CRASHOVERRIDE (ICS malware attacking Ukraine grid operator) and recently the TRITON/TRISIS/Hatman (attack tool against safety system). In Sweden, IT security incidents led to the resignation of two ministers from the government, and a journalists use of Shodan led to that one of Swedens largest news room had a series of reports on what is Internet accessible, when they found heating/hydropower/windpower/elevators and more, sitting on the Internet for anyone to access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM 2017 summit (previously known as 4SICS) had several presentations related to all these issues. As a holiday gift for you, we have now published a number of presentations on our YouTube channel: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkD15o_9eJxUc9eeHtWSQ6Q&quot;&gt;CS3STHLM at YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next year we will be back for the fifth time and the dates are October 22nd-25th. We are already on the lookout for summit content, so do let us know what you think we should present in order to make next years workshops and conference as useful and rewarding as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another holiday gift is that we already have opened the ticket sale for 2018 with a special Earliest Bird discount of 30 % on the two-day conference ticket. Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/&quot;&gt;www.cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt; and the discounted ticket is available until January 12th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very happy holiday season - from all of us, to all of you! 
The CS3STHLM crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2017/12/20/cs3sthlm-newsletter-december.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2017/12/20/cs3sthlm-newsletter-december.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Presents ICS- and IoT Lab together with Norwegian Energy CERT</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the light of growing vulnerabilities, this year’s top summit on Cyber Security in Industrial Control Systems and Critical Infrastructure will give delegates possibilities to partake in real-time simulations and challenges in an updated and bigger ICS lab. The lab is hosted by ROMAB, Norwegian Energy CERT and equipment provided by the Norwegian National Security Authority, NSM. The summit takes place in Stockholm October 24-26.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year the lab is declared to be bigger, better and more interesting than ever before with added ICS and ICS communication equipment to the lab. New equipment has resulted in a simulation of communication in industrial control systems with some ICS specific protocols including OPC communication being in progress. It is also extended with a part that is for IoT security. The Internet of things, (IoT), is the network of physical devices, vehicles, and other items embedded with electronics, software, sensors, actuators, and network connectivity which enable these objects to collect and exchange data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Margrete Raaum from Norwegian Energy CERT:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;-”Nothing gives as valuable cyber security learning as real hands-on work. Teaming up with ROMAB to create a dynamic and realistic learning environment is exciting, and we hope this will benefit ICS security engineers all over Scandinavia and beyond”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year there is a much larger team involved in setting up, running the lab, or have special tasks involving the lab during the conference. The team members include Lars-Erik Smevold of KraftCERT (NO) who will be in charge of the lab, Nicklas Keijser (SE), who is an expert on SCADA/ICS development, Robert Malmgren (SE) of ROMAB, Erik Hjelmvik (SE) of NETRESEC and Mikael Vingaard (DK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert Malmgren, founder of CS3STHLM and owner of ROMAB elaborates:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;-”We are honored to have the Norwegian energy sector CERT KraftCERT, as cooperators to ROMAB in setting up this year hosting the ICS and IoT security lab! This is a truly great partnership over the border with our Scandinavian friends in an effort to build competence and relationships for all that strive to secure the society and its critical infrastructure by starting with its fundamentals - the very systems that run our basic functions, like the electrical grid. Thank you to the Norwegian National Security Authority (NSM)  to lending out equipment to the lab”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/press/2017/10/04/cs3sthlm-presents-ics-and-iot-lab-together-with-norwegian-energy-cert.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press/2017/10/04/cs3sthlm-presents-ics-and-iot-lab-together-with-norwegian-energy-cert.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>press</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Advenica announces new collaboration with CS3STHLM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The 4th edition of the top international summit on SCADA/ICS and critical infrastructure includes a seminar called ’Effective threat mitigation strategies’ hosted by Advenica. The company is providing new ways in cyber security, protecting critical infrastructures with innovative solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the founders of CS3STHLM, Robert Malmgren, expresses excitement over the collaboration;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;” This fits perfectly with our profile and we are looking forward to learn about Advenica’s new security solutions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advenica elaborates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”Last years have presented an increasing number of bumps in the road for cyber security defenders. The vast number of different attack vectors and the explosion in number of malware variants has made yesterday’s cyber defense strategies obsolete. The goal of cyber security is to ensure robust operation of the defended system – not to find as many pieces of malware as possible. Yesterday’s strategy is efficient at finding malware – but fail in ensuring robust operation”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM is an international summit that focus entirely on cyber security protection of SCADA/ICS and critical infrastructure. CS3STHLM attracts about 250-300 people from around the world to meet, network and gain knowledge. CS3STHLM takes place October 23-26 at the venue Nalen in central Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/press/2017/09/14/advenica-announces-new-collaboration-with-cs3sthlm.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press/2017/09/14/advenica-announces-new-collaboration-with-cs3sthlm.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>press</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter September</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM summit is just a bit over a month away. Today we have speakers from many corners of the earth, and we have already attendees from most continents!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be at the beutiful venue Nalen in central Stockholm again.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;speakers-and-presentations&quot;&gt;Speakers and presentations &lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have presentations on various topics, including:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how security impact safety&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;how to sucessfully roll out cyber security policies at multinational corporations  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Security (or the lack thereof) in IoT  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;First hand accounts of the ongoing Ukraine cyber attacks  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New, secure, protocols for SCADA/ICS  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lessons learned from handling an enourmous APT at a critical infrastructure provider&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn about tricks and defense in Social Engineering  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always we will have a mix of attack and defence stances, between technology and policy level, between theory and real-dirt-under-your-nails practise. We will continue the tradition from 4SICS to use multiple stages, and presentations will be done in different formats – a main stage, a TV studio setup for more intimate atmosphere and dialogues, and an impromptu stage in GeekLounge for improvised presentations (lightning talks, work in progress presentations, etc).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View speaker info here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;/speakers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View info on presentations here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&quot;&gt;/presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;workshops&quot;&gt;Workshops &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are fortunate to have three excellent pre-conference trainings/tutorials:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/workshops/erik-hjelmvik/&quot;&gt;Network Forensics (2 day) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/workshops/mikael-vingaard/&quot;&gt;Practical SCADA/ICS Honeypots (1 day) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/program/workshops/michael-theuerzeit/&quot;&gt;Cyber Security for Industrial Automation and Control Systems: An introduction of the IEC 62443 
standard (1 day) &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tickets for all different workshops are available now. Please remember that one workshop is 2 day and the others are 1 day. If you select the 2 day workshop, make sure that you arrive and can start monday morning!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;security-lab-ics-and-iot&quot;&gt;Security lab: ICS and IoT &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we will have a larger and more professional ICS security lab in place. Besides the number of equipment available, we will also help interested attendees to better play with it at their level of knowledge. Beginners will find help to do basic probeing and pokeing at exotic devices. Intermediates will be able to do more advanced experiments with bugs. Experts will be able to participate in winning prices if they submit newly found vulnerabilities to the CERT representatives at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we will also introduce an IoT security lab where people can play around with SOHO equipment, lightbulbs with IP addresses, embedded devices, etc.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;practical-things&quot;&gt;Practical things &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still have rooms left in the block with discounts that we negotiated with the hotel closest to the venue. We want to inform you that rooms are going quickly and the cut-of-date for when the discount is no longer available is less than two weeks away. Dont miss out on having this!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Info on venue, dates, airports, subways, hotels, etc can be found at the info web here:  &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se/practical-details/&quot;&gt;/practical-details&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;historic-presentations&quot;&gt;Historic presentations &lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get a taste of what the summit is, you can find old presentations from 2015 and 2016 on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCkD15o_9eJxUc9eeHtWSQ6Q&quot;&gt;youtube/cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2017/09/13/cs3sthlm-newsletter-september.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2017/09/13/cs3sthlm-newsletter-september.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
