<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS3STHLM</title>
    <description>CS3sthlm, the premier Cyber Security Conference for ICS/SCADA and Critical Infrastructure, annually in October with pre-summit Trainings and Expo.</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 13:58:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter May 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To all friends of CS3STHLM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is with great sadness we communicate the cancellation of the 2021 CS3STHLM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many others worldwide, we are going through a challenging period during this period of pandemic and that affects business as well as private issues. Due to the challenges of arranging a global conference in a time of a global pandemic, we have decided that there is missing basis for what we aim to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who want to support our mission of keeping up the knowledge-sharing, we recommend digging into our video-on-demand material available here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://vod.cs3sthlm.com/product/cs3sthlm-2020-video-on-demand/&quot;&gt;https://vod.cs3sthlm.com/product/cs3sthlm-2020-video-on-demand/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To all alumni and friends - take care in the pandemic and continue to protect all control systems!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole CS3Sthlm crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2021/05/10/cs3sthlm-newsletter-may.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2021/05/10/cs3sthlm-newsletter-may.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter December 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hohoho!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you read this Stockholm has passed the winter solstice (Mo 21 Dec 11.02 local time) and is finally going in the right direction! At least regarding daylight time, which with Sweden’s zero hours of visible sun should not be too hard to achieve. We are also near the holidays, which we would like to celebrate by giving you all a gift!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ross-andersonss-presentation-on-the-cs3sthlm-youtube-channel&quot;&gt;Ross Andersons’s presentation on the CS3STHLM YouTube channel!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keynote presentation from CS3STHLM 2020 has been uploaded to our YouTube channel. The keynote was given by the inspirational Ross J Anderson, Professor of Security Engineering at the Department of Computer Science and Technology, at the University of Cambridge. So we wish you all a Happy Hogmanay with this link to the presentation:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jX2CoZkz8J4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you might have heard of the ongoing &lt;strong&gt;SUNBURST/SOLORIGATE&lt;/strong&gt; incident. This is a major incident and the impact grows while the investigations uncover more and more TTP’s, victims and other info. Many of CS3sthlm alumni has been active in covering this, done in-depth analysis or helpt creating tools to do post mortem analysis. Here are some of them:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Joe Slowik has a great text at the Domaintools blog -
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.domaintools.com/resources/blog/continuous-eruption-further-analysis-of-the-solarwinds-supply-incident&quot;&gt;https://www.domaintools.com/resources/blog/continuous-eruption-further-analysis-of-the-solarwinds-supply-incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Kim Zetter has covered several things including early signs -
&lt;a href=&quot;https://news.yahoo.com/hackers-last-year-conducted-a-dry-run-of-solar-winds-breach-215232815.html&quot;&gt;https://news.yahoo.com/hackers-last-year-conducted-a-dry-run-of-solar-winds-breach-215232815.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Erik Hjelmvik has a tool to reassemble victim data -
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.netresec.com/?page=Blog&amp;amp;month=2020-12&amp;amp;post=Reassembling-Victim-Domain-Fragments-from-SUNBURST-DNS&quot;&gt;https://www.netresec.com/?page=Blog&amp;amp;month=2020-12&amp;amp;post=Reassembling-Victim-Domain-Fragments-from-SUNBURST-DNS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Rob M. Lee of Dragos has  been interviewed multiple times, for example
for CBS new - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/i/status/1339720071946625033&quot;&gt;https://twitter.com/i/status/1339720071946625033&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-2020-video-on-demand-tickets-are-for-sale&quot;&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 Video on Demand tickets are for sale!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is EUR 299 (including Swedish VAT 25%) and it gives you access to all presentations from the October event to watch whenever it suits you the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, when buying the CS3STHLM 2020 VoD service you will be granted the purchase amount as a discount on next year’s Summit, be it physical or digital – or both!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This link will get you to the registration page: &lt;a href=&quot;https://vod.cs3sthlm.com/&quot;&gt;https://vod.cs3sthlm.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM 2020 presentations will not be available on YouTube as they usually are. Except for Ross Anderson, as said above!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/12/21/cs3sthlm-newsletter-december.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/12/21/cs3sthlm-newsletter-december.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter November 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings from a Stockholm that this time of year can easily be summarized with the color grey. We bring you good news on how to handle early winter and Corona restrictions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-2020-video-on-demand-tickets-are-for-sale&quot;&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 Video on Demand tickets are for sale!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is &lt;strong&gt;EUR 299&lt;/strong&gt; (including Swedish VAT 25%) and it gives you access to all presentations from the October event to watch whenever it suits you the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, when buying the CS3STHLM 2020 VoD service you will be granted the purchase amount as a discount on next year’s Summit, be it physical or digital – or both!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM 2020 presentations will &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; be available on YouTube as they usually are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training&quot;&gt;Training!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, during the CS3STHLM event this year we did not manage to arrange any trainings or workshops. Now we have been discussing to start an “ICS Gym” activity already the coming spring, and we would love to have some input from you on that issue. What type of training would you need to expand your knowledge? Are you experienced in something that others might need to learn? Every type of subject within the Cyber Security range, and in length from 20 minutes to 2 days are of interest for us. Please give us your thoughts on the whats and hows of knowledge sharing to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/11/26/cs3sthlm-newsletter-novemeber.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/11/26/cs3sthlm-newsletter-novemeber.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM 2020 - Thank You!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3sthlm-logo-heart.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Thank You&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-3-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM of 2020 is over, and a reflection is that the virtual event went even better than we could hope for. The basis of CS3STHLM is the content, and we are familliar with that part – but everything else in the event production was new to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the organizing side of CS3STHLM, we would like to express our warmest gratitude to everyone involved in making this years Summit, Expo and Sessions such a success! We would like to give a big shoutout to all content providers and speakers, trainers - without you the event would not have been possible, and it was a honour to work with you! Special thanks goes out to our partners: Accenture Security, Darktrace, Kaspersky, Recorded Future, Sectra, sysctl, Trend Micro, Waterfall Security Solutions and also to the crews at Dynamic Duo, WeareBryssel, Scenteknik, Nikka systems, and all staff at Nalen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a content provider - we have already opened the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:cfp@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;cfp@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt; for submissions to the 2021 event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have critics, comments or ideas for enhancements we would like to hear from you. Everything that can make CS3STHLM even better we would like to know! Mail us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have ideas for topics, presenters, content, areas of special interest, things that earns a deep dive, please reach out to us at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:info@cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;info@cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your input is important to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once again – thank you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/10/23/cs3sthlm-thank-you.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/10/23/cs3sthlm-thank-you.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>EXTRA PRESS RELEASE FROM CS3STHLM</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;NORTHERN EUROPE’S LEADING CONFERENCE ON CYBER SECURITY AND ICS/SCADA, CS3STHLM, ANNOUNCES,:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy Greenberg, author of ”Sandworm: A New Era of Cyberwar and the Hunt for the Kremlin’s Most Dangerous Hackers”  will appear live on link to comment the fact that Sandworm is yet again making headlines thanks to the unsealing of Department of Justice/FBI indictment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the dramatic events this week Andy Greenberg has agreed to partake live on link in CS3STHLM on this specific subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert Malmgren, co founder of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”-We are so grateful that Andy has made time for us in his extremely busy schedule, it’s invaluable to get a direct comment from a world leading authority!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/press/2020/10/22/cs3sthlm-press-extra.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press/2020/10/22/cs3sthlm-press-extra.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>press</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM seventh conference on Cyber Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This years Summit on Cyber Security in Industrial Control Systems and Critical Infrastructure takes place in October 21-22 – but in cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 is looking forward to a successful meeting for leading cyber security experts from around the world. This year the event will be virtual due to the pandemic situation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We are really excited to get the outstanding &lt;strong&gt;Ross Andersen&lt;/strong&gt;, Professor of Security Engineering at University of Cambridge as our keynote speaker this year. He is a true pioneer in the Cyber Security field, and has just written the third edition of his textbook bible ”Security Engineering – A Guide to Building Dependable Distributed Systems” which will be released in November, says Robert Malmgren, founder of CS3STHLM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM also says welcome back to &lt;strong&gt;Jenny Radcliffe&lt;/strong&gt; – the People Hacker, nominated for the UK Godmother of Cyber Security award this year! She will, during the Tuesday evening Welcome Reception, present ”Cunning Corona – on deception, scams and social engineering in a pandemic”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable for this year is that the purchase of a ticket to the CS3STHLM 2020 Summit also gives you the possibility to watch the whole program by &lt;strong&gt;VoD, Video on Demand&lt;/strong&gt;. At first, directly from the event platform during the time that the CS3 Summit is live, and later from our web site &lt;a href=&quot;https://cs3sthlm.se&quot;&gt;/cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;. The presentations will not be available on YouTube as they usually are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM Partner Expo, usually arranged the day before the CS3STHLM Summit, is now integrated into the two days of the Summit, and the conference participants can visit exhibitors in the platforms Expo section, or take part in partner sessions.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM Expo is not only a great opportunity to network and discuss the market field for interested parties, but will also consist of exciting demonstrations and presentations from researchers and vendors, says Erik Johansson from Omnisiens.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/press/2020/10/15/cs3sthlm-press-october.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press/2020/10/15/cs3sthlm-press-october.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>press</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter October</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More news on our upcoming event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keynote-by-world-famous-author-professor-ross-andersen&quot;&gt;Keynote by world famous author Professor Ross Andersen!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This years keynote speaker is no other than the outstanding Ross Andersen from University of Cambridge Computer Laboratory, UK. He is the author of the now classic book ”Security Engineering” first published in 2001, and is now revising the third edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;welcome-reception-on-tuesday-evening-oct-20th&quot;&gt;Welcome Reception on Tuesday evening Oct 20th!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do not miss the Welcome Reception in the evening before the start of the Summit. There will be useful walk-throughs of our conference platform Hopin and our interactive tool Mentimeter, an interactive Quiz and more. We are also really proud to welcome back one of our favorite speakers, Jenny Radcliffe – The People Hacker!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-2020-video-on-demand&quot;&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 Video on Demand!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notable for this year is that the purchase of a ticket to the CS3STHLM 2020 Summit also gives you the possibility to watch the whole program by VoD. At first, directly from the Hopin platform during the time that the CS3 Summit is live, and later from our web site www.cs3sthlm.se. The presentations will not be available on YouTube as they usually are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tickets-are-for-sale&quot;&gt;Tickets are for sale!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the ticket here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/&quot;&gt;/cs3sthlm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is EUR 299 (including VAT 25%) and is not refundable. When buying tickets, you will have to register name and email on the Hopin platform. Then you will first receive a simple transaction receipt via &lt;a href=&quot;https://hopin.to/events/cs3sthlm-2020&quot;&gt;Hopin&lt;/a&gt;, but you will also receive a detailed receipt via email from CS3STHLM within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/10/12/cs3sthlm-newsletter-october.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/10/12/cs3sthlm-newsletter-october.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM seventh conference on Cyber Security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This years Summit on Cyber Security in Industrial Control Systems and Critical Infrastructure takes place in October 21-22 – but in cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CS3STHLM 2020 is looking forward to a successful meeting for leading cyber security experts from around the world. This year the event will be virtual due to the pandemic situation.
 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;robert-malmgren-from-omnisiens&quot;&gt;Robert Malmgren from Omnisiens:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We had to adapt to the situation, and it took us a long time to find a way to move our event to a virtual platform without losing quality or content. Now we are proud and happy to once again announce an impressive line-up of speakers, covering a broad spectra of knowledge in the Cyber Security sphere. We have also brought with us the same production professionals that we usually work together with, to ensure quality and to try to transfer some of the CS3STHLM feeling onto the virtual stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new feature for CS3STHLM is that all material later will be available as VoD, Video on Demand, for all ticket holders. This is to make the content easily accessible at all times, compensating for the time zones differences around the globe.
 
The CS3STHLM Partner Expo, usually arranged the day before the CS3STHLM Summit, is now integrated into the two days of the Summit, and the conference participants can visit exhibitors in the platforms Expo section, or take part in partner sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The CS3STHLM Expo is not only a great opportunity to network and discuss the market field for interested parties, but will also consist of exciting demonstrations and presentations from researchers and vendors says Erik Johansson from Omnisiens.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/press/2020/09/24/cs3sthlm-seventh-conference.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/press/2020/09/24/cs3sthlm-seventh-conference.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>press</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Newsletter September</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cs3-ticket-2020.png&quot; alt=&quot;CS3STHLM Thank You&quot; class=&quot;post-image-full-width col-2-8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;News on our upcoming event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-virtual-summit-of-2020&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Virtual Summit of 2020!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditional CS3 Summit content, presentations, partner exhibitions and social events will be happening online on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://hopin.to/events/cs3sthlm-2020&quot;&gt;Hopin platform&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of travelling to Stockholm, you can now participate in the CS3STHLM event from wherever you want. And to counter time zone differences and offer the best accessibility, you can as a ticket holder, either participate in the live event (CET Stockholm time zone Oct 21-22), or watch it later as VOD, Video on Demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tickets-are-for-sale&quot;&gt;Tickets are for sale!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the ticket here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/&quot;&gt;cs3sthlm.se&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ticket price is EUR 299 (including VAT 25%) and is not refundable. When buying tickets, you will have to register name and email on the Hopin platform. Then you will first receive a simple transaction receipt via Hopin, but you will also receive a detailed receipt via email from CS3STHLM within 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-trainings-&quot;&gt;No trainings ☹&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sorry, but we could not manage to move the trainings into our virtual platform this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-expo&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Expo!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the Expo will be running in parallel on the platform during the CS3sthlm Summit Oct 21-22. Do visit our partners and check out their virtual exhibitions and sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cs3sthlm-summit-agenda&quot;&gt;CS3sthlm Summit agenda!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see the Summit agenda here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/agenda/&quot;&gt;/agenda&lt;/a&gt;. Do also check out our impressive line-up of speakers here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/speakers/&quot;&gt;/speakers&lt;/a&gt;
and you can find the presentations here - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cs3sthlm.se/program/presentations/&quot;&gt;/presentations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best wishes from the CS3STHLM crew &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/09/17/cs3sthlm-newsletter-septepmber.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/09/17/cs3sthlm-newsletter-septepmber.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CS3STHLM Goes Virtual</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The COVID situation is problematic for all. For a long time we waited to see if it would be possible to run CS3 in Nalen as we have done for the last 5 years. We have now, after many meetings and discussions, decided to go fully virtual for 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The traditional courses, presentations and social events will exist, but go online. We will add new formats and ideas, such as meetups, to the 2020 edition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details will be posted in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CS3sthlm team&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>/news/2020/07/10/cs3sthlm-goes-virtual.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/news/2020/07/10/cs3sthlm-goes-virtual.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>news</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
